# **Ariel Montes**

# Software Developer

+39 393 097 0530

✓ info@montesariel.com

www.montesariel.com





I'm a full stack web developer, graduated as "Superior Technician for Smart City & Energy Clean Management" in the biennial ITS / EQF5 course organized by "Fondazione Green" and its partners (Stiima-CNR and UniBs) and previously graduated from a three-year Technical School with the title of "Computer Technician". I'm a software development and digital art enthusiast, constantly improving my skills thought a "learn by doing" approach.

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

#### Software Developer

Ethea | 11/2020 - Present

Software Developer - Web designer. Among the projects that have been assigned to me, Sport <u>Club Manager</u> stands out, a management software used by sports clubs.

- Web & Desktop app development in Delphi.
- Database, scripting and backup management.
- Creation and maintenance of technical documentation.
- System integration and control version.
- Web design, images, logos and svg.
- Remote teamwork.

Software Developer

Tecnimex | 01/2020 - 07/2020

Apprenticeship. Web app development, system integration, control version and teamwork.

**Enterprising Artist** 

Freelance | 2012 - 2018

Graphic Designer for private clients and companies. Disign of logos and advertising images, create a website to promote my services, customer management and photo retouching.

Computer Technician

Editorial M.E.S | 07/2007 - 08/2008

Apprenticeship. System / network administrator and helpdesk in-house.

# **PROJECTS**

**Dustbin IoT** Open Source

This project was conceived as a thesis for the biennial ITS course: "Superior Technician for Smart City & Clean Energy Management". It's an intelligent system for managing the refuse collection of a Smart City. It is a fully functional web application written in Python / Django and deployed in Heroku. As database it uses PostgreSQL leaning on the Django ORM, and Javascript, HTML and CSS for the frontend.

Hidden Folder Open Source

Personal project that was born from my desire to hide some folders when leaving my usb to colleagues. The usefulness of this program is to hide any folder effectively from Windows OS interface even on USB devices, so that these folders remain hidden on different computers.

## SKILLS

#### **Technical**

JavaScript/CSS/Bootstrap

Python/Delphi

MSSQL/PostgreSQL

#### Professional

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

Project management

## **EDUCATION**

Superior Technician for Smart City & Clean Energy Management (ITS / EQF5)

Fondazione Green

2018 - 2020 Cer.

### Computer Technician

Polytechnic Institute:

"Pablo de la Torriente Brau"

2004 - 2007 Cer.

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)

Italian (Advanced)

# INTERESTS

Technology

Photogrphy

Travelling

